

DZMITRY SHEMETJunior Front-end Developer

Phone: +375 (44) 493 48 79

Email: dmitrishemet@gmail.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/dmitry-shemet
GitHub: https://github.com/DimitarShemet

Hi, my name is Dmitry. I work now as Front-End engineer in the IT-school. Current project is the development of the learning web portal «The Lessoner» which has a high priority for the company. Together with PM I worked on project specification, designing a project in Figma, creating tickets (we work using agile process). I am very good team player and always support my colleges in case they have problem with the code. My tasks require solid knowledge in React.js, TypeScript, SCSS HTML.

SKILLS

- ✓ HTML
- ✓ CSS
- ✓ SCSS
- ✓ JavaScript
 - ES6
 - *OOP*
 - AJAX
 - SPA
 - DOM
 - JSON
 - Canvas
 - Render tree
 - Arrow functions
 - Event Loop
- ✓ TypeScript
- ✓ React
 - Styled Components
 - Functional Components
 - JSX
 - React Router
 - React-intl

- ✓ Redux
- ✓ Webpack
- ✓ Babel
- ✓ Git, GitHub,
- ✓ Figma
- ✓ StoryBook
- ✓ Jira
- ✓ Agile development process
- ✓ English: B1 ✓ German: A2

EXPERIENCE

2022 Front End developer, IT-Academy.

Current project: Development of learning web portal for thew school. **Responsibilities included:**

Developing web-application with functional React components using TypeScript, website layout, internationalization of the project, Storybook implementation, React Routing, Rendering data from the backend, REST API. GitHub: https://github.com/IT-Academy-Ruby/lessoner_project_frontend

2022 Trainee, Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy)

Project description: Online shop «React pizza»
Responsibilities included: Developing web application with
class React components, dynamic application rendering, active use of Redux,
AJAX, React Router, adaptive for tablets and mobile devices

Link: https://chic-nougat-ef09f4.netlify.app/

2022 Trainee, Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy)

Project description: Single page application "Flappy birds" game Responsibilities included: Developing a web application with vanilla JS, AJAX, JavaScript Routing, adaptive for tablets and mobile devices

Link: https://dimitarshemet.github.io/Js-Diplom/

2021 — 2022 Trainee, Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy)

Project description: Louvre museum website Responsibilities included: Layout selection, website layout, adaptive for tablets and mobile devices

Link: https://dimitarshemet.github.io/IT-Academy/

2021 — 2022 Engineer-technologist, Unitsky String Technologies Inc

Responsibilities included: Development of new types of products, Creation of production, Selection of technological equipment

2020 — 2021 Chemist, Alnilam

Responsibilities included:

Development of new types of products, production of cosmetic products.

EDUCATION

06.2022 — 08.2022 Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy)

Course: DEVELOPING WEB APPLICATIONS USING REACT

Certificate: <u>link</u> Grade: 10

02.2022 — 06.2022 Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy)

Course: WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT WITH JAVASCRIPT

Certificate: <u>link</u> Grade: 9

10.2021 — 01.2022 Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy)

Course: WEBSITE DEVELOPMENT WITH HTML, CSS & JAVASCRIPT

Certificate: <u>link</u> Grade: 9

2015 — 2020 Belarusian State Technological University, Minsk, Belarus,

Bachelor's degree in Biotechnology with honor